github.com/nicksun1 US/Canada Dual Citizen

- Nicholas Sun -

nicksun1.github.io

Updated 07/2021 **Q**

in linkedin.com/in/nicholas-sun-ln

(573) 639-2388

Summary

Profile Statistician and data scientist with extensive experience performing analysis on massive,

complex datasets. Interested in development of interpretable and robust tools backed by superior

quantitative operating characteristics.

Areas of Expertise · Statistical methodology development, large-scale simulation studies, predictive modeling,

development of visualization tools. Clinical trials and biomarker studies.

Frequently used · R, Python, SAS, Spotfire, SQL.

Education

M.S. Biostatistics, Columbia University	New York, NY	August 2016-2018
B.S. Mechanical Engineering, Columbia University	New York, NY	August 2012-2016

Professional Experience

Eli Lilly and Company Senior Statistician

July 2018-Present *Indianapolis, IN*

- · Lead team to create cross-therapeutic automated visualization tools for adverse events reporting in phase 1 clinical trials. Utilization increases reliability and decreases phase I dose-escalation review timeline five-fold. Recipient of Lilly Innovator Award 2020.
- · Propose biomarker prediction model for novel analysis of large scale patient data. Methodology adopted by various groups working across multiple drug compounds after determination of positive value.
- · Develop dose-response models to inform stop-and-go strategies for SAD and MAD phase 1 clinical trials. Rigorous simulation study and methodology presented in internal technical report.
- · Manage production, maintenance, and review of evidence packages submitted to FDA for drug approval.
- · Create versatile R packages in analysis and visualization of multiple simultaneous variables for novel closed loop insulin pump patient date over time.
- · Build data-driven risk matrix of COVID-19 effect on trial endpoints to inform company-wide decision making process on continuation, viability and pivot direction of all new and on-going clinical trials.
- · Head team for original Lilly initiative for handling and dissemination of confidential study data for public use.
- · Contribute to Eli Lilly publications in various academic journals.

National Institute of Health

May 2017-August 2017

Statistician, Biostatistics and Biometrics Branch

Bethesda, MD

- · Developed new composite inference strategy for performing tests on differences in means with zero-inflated data.
- · Authored report recommending new nutritional guidelines based on reanalysis of childhood nutrition dataset.

Software

- · PowerCompareZero R package that includes various functions to compare, test, and run new inference procedures for analysis of semi-continuous data.
- · InsulinSensitivity R and SAS project evaluating best use case for common measure of insulin sensitivity accounting for available information and efficiency and depth of desired conclusion.

Skills and Interests

- · Language Proficiency: Mandarin Full Professional; Spanish Intermediate
- · Community Involvement: Lilly service volunteer Boy Scouts of America (Crossroads of America Council).
- · Interests: snowboarding, hiking, ultimate frisbee, fantasy football, online gaming.